Lelah Bates Childs

Full Stack Engineer

contact

phone

(612) 695-6190

email

labchilds@gmail.com

address

533 Ocean Ave apt B5 Brooklyn, NY 11226

github

github.com/labchild

website

labchild.github.io/labchild-react-portfolio

technical skills

- » HTML5, CSS, JavaScript
- » Browser-based libraries (Bootstrap & jQuery)
- » Server-side development (MERN stack, PWAs)
- » Databases (MySql & MonqoDB)
- » ORM & ODM (Sequelize & Mongoose)
- » API interaction (REST, JSON, AJAX, GraphQL)
- » Unit testing
- » Adobe Creative Suite (Illustrator, Photoshop, InDesign)

education

Columbia University
New York, NY - Certificate
SEPT 2021 - MARCH 2022
Completed with 97% average

Skidmore College

Saratoga Springs, NY - BS AUG 2010 - MAY 2014 Bachelor of Science in Studio Art

Additional Coursework SVA, NYC - Advertising LdM, Florence, Italy -Design & Illustration

summary

Curious and creative problem-solver transitioning to a career in tech. Strengths in frontend and backend development and experience with the MERN stack. I'm excited to leverage and grow my current skill set as part of a motivated team making the internet a better place.

projects

FRIDAY, fridayyy.co - Frontend, UX/UI
MAY - JUNE 2022

Created a custom theme for a Shopify store selling weekly boxes of home-made food to the Greater NYC area.

Kitchen Sink, kitchen-sink.herokuapp.com — *Backend* MARCH 2022

Designed a NoSQL database and API using GraphQL for a user-seeded recipe sharing forum. This project was built in 10 days.

Let's Eat!, a-breezy.github.io/LetsEat - Frontend, UX/UI
NOVEMBER 2021

Designed the UI for a random restaurant generator based on Yelp's API, with dynamic styling. This project was built in 10 days.

experience

Verblio, Remote — *CONTRACT: Copy Editor and SEO Specialist* FEBRUARY 2021 — PRESENT

Edited and optimized 30+ purchased blog articles and other written content per month.

Gran Tivoli, New York, NY — *Bartender* SEPTEMBER 2019 — MARCH 2020

Mixed and served classic, contemporary, and specialty cocktails in a casual-fine dining restaurant and associated speakeasy.

The Cauldron Pub & Magical Experience, New York, NY – Assistant General Manager

APRIL 2019 - SEPTEMBER 2020

Managed front and back of house operations for a 2-story cocktail bar and gastropub that averaged 100-250 covers per night.

City Winery, New York, NY — Bartender, Manager NOVEMBER 2014 — APRIL 2019

Mixed and served cocktails in a 400-seat concert venue and attached wine bar with extensive winelist. Beginning Oct 2018, managed the front of house operations for 500-1400 covers per night.

The Hub Soho by Superchief Gallery, New York, NY — Operations & Events Coordinator

DECEMBER 2015 - DECEMBER 2016

Managed social media profiles, posting at least once per day; wrote and designed all wall text for shows; organized and executed 2-4 events per month, including launches and release parties for muscians and PAPER magazine.

Lyssé, New York, NY — *Ecommerce Assistant* JANUARY 2015 — NOVEMBER 2015

Wrote and designed 2 marketing emails per week; wrote copy for 15-30 new products and designed banner ads each launch.